{
    "id": "d9bab78ef55c4353912a47807063e3cd",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He is rich ………………….. he is not happy.",
            "description": "We use but to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "but",
                "though"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He sells oranges …………………… mangoes.",
            "description": "We use as well as to add.",
            "answers": [
                "as well",
                "also",
                "as well as"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I honor him ………………… he is an honest man.",
            "description": "We use because to give the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "though",
                "so",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We decided to go out ……………….. it was very late.",
            "description": "We use although to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "although",
                "however",
                "even if"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He sat down ………………… he was tired.",
            "description": "We use because to give the reason for something.",
            "answers": [
                "though",
                "so",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You must be quiet …………………. you must leave the room.",
            "description": "We use or to present an alternative.",
            "answers": [
                "or",
                "while",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is neither a knave ……………….. a fool.",
            "description": "We can combine two negative ideas with neither…nor.",
            "answers": [
                "or",
                "either",
                "nor"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I will come …………………. I have time.",
            "description": "We use if to express a condition.",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "if",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I went to the shop ……………….. bought some pens.",
            "description": "We use and to merely add one statement to another.",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "to",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for him ………………… he arrived.",
            "description": "We use until to show time.",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "without",
                "if"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He bled so profusely ……………… he died.",
            "description": "The conjunction so that can express cause and effect.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "that",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You will not get the prize ……………….. you deserve it.",
            "description": "We use unless to express a condition. It is similar to if not.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "unless",
                "whether"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}